(新八)ﾌﾝ！ ﾌﾝ！ ﾌﾝ…！
(お妙)精が出るわね 新ちゃん｡
I see you're working hard, Shin-chan.
あっ 姉上 すみません｡
Ah, Sis.
Sorry about making such a racket with my swishing.
ﾌﾞﾝﾌﾞﾝﾌﾞﾝﾌﾞﾝ うるさくて｡
Did I wake you up?
起こしてしまいましたか？
Well, I'd call that swooshing instead of swishing...
いや ﾌﾞﾝﾌﾞﾝじゃなくて ﾌﾝﾌﾝが｡
But it's fine.
でも いいのよ｡ 構わず続けて｡
Don't mind me. Continue.
すみません 気をつけます｡
I'm sorry. I'll be careful.
ﾊﾝ！ ﾊﾝ！ ﾊﾝ…！
Shin-chan.
新ちゃん
そういう問題じゃないのよ｡
That's not the issue here.
ﾊﾝ！ ﾊﾝ…！
掛け声 変えても何も意味が…｡
Changing your cry won't accomplish anything...
ﾊﾝ！ ﾊﾝ…！
((２人:うおぉ～！))
I want to become stronger...
《強くなりたい》
((おわぁ～！
(神楽)やめろ～！
Stop!
ｸﾞﾊｯ！
(神楽)やめろ～!!))
So I'm not the one being protected all the time...
《守られるばかりじゃなく➡
So I can protect everyone else!
ﾎﾞｸも みんなを守れるくらい…》
♪♪～
((神威:弱いﾔﾂに用はないって))
...I don't have use for weaklings.
Big...!
I want to become stronger...
《神楽:強くなりたい》
I'll protect Kagura!
((神楽ちゃんはﾎﾞｸが守る！
I'll protect the Kagura we believe in!
ﾎﾞｸらが信じる神楽ちゃんを
守るんだ！))
《神威に…
自分に負けないくらい》
So I won't lose to Kamui... or myself...
[Stronger]
(新八/神楽)強く！
Stronger!
強く…｡
なりたいんです ﾎﾞｸたち｡
We...
...want to become stronger.
"All Adults are Instructors for All Children."
Yeah? Then do it.
(銀時)ふ～ん なればいいじゃん｡
がんばってね｡
Good luck.
That's all you have to say?
いや がんばってねじゃなくて｡
Wait, weren't you listening to our monologue before the episode title?
えっ 見てなかったんですか？
ｻﾌﾞﾀｲﾄﾙ前｡
結構ｼﾘｱｽな感じで
ｱﾚなんですけど…｡
I mean... we had that serious look and all...
Building up to a whole training arc thing after running into enemies stronger than anything we've seen...
今までにない強敵と対峙して➡
修行編に突入するんだなぁ
みたいな…｡
What training arc?
修行編って何？
That's what you guys are about to start?
そんなもんに突入するの？
お前たち｡
Sounds rough.
大変だね｡
いや そうじゃなくて➡
No, not that.
Isn't there some kind of special training... you know?
なんか特訓とか… ねぇ？
That you can teach us...?
ﾎﾞｸらに教えたりとか｡
そうそう｡
That's right!
だいたい
銀ちゃんだって修行が必要ね｡
You need to do some training too, Gin-chan.
We've got lots of tough enemies coming up.
これから強敵いっぱいね｡
強く…｡
なりたいんです ﾎﾞｸたち｡
We...
...want to become stronger.
And so, three months passed.
Man, that was some tough training.
いやぁ 大変だったなぁ修行｡
流れてねえよ ものの
３秒くらいしか流れてねえよ！
Three months haven't passed!
Only three seconds have passed!
でもやっぱり
我が家がいちばんだなぁ｡
It's good to be home.
なにﾅﾚｰｼｮﾝで修行 終えた感じに
しようとしてんだ！
Why does your narration make it sound like you've been training?!
Don't worry.
心配いらねえさ｡
The flow of time here and there is different.
向こうと こっちじゃ
時間の流れが違う｡
A month over there isn't even a second over here.
向こうでの１か月は
こっちの１秒にも満たないからな｡
向こうって何だよ!?
全然 意味わかんねえよ！
Where is over there?!
You're making no sense at all!!
It means that in three seconds here,
３秒でも ｵﾚたちは向こうで
３か月の成果を得たってわけさ｡
we were able to reap the benefits of training three months over there.
We never moved an inch from here!
一歩たりとも
ここから動いてねえんだよ｡
And where is over there for crying out loud?!
だから何？ 向こうって！
Since when did we train in the Room of Spirit and Time?!
[Note: Room of Spirit and Time - Training space that appears in the Dxxxxn Baxx series.]
なんで 精神と時の部屋で
修行したことになってんの！
What's wrong with that?
いいだろ こんな感じで｡
もう終わったことにしとこうぜ｡
Let's just say we got it over with.
It's such a pain.
もう めんどくせえよ｡
I don't wanna do any training.
修行なんてやりたくねえよ｡
It's such a pain.
そんな めんどくさい｡
He just said something a JUMP main character would never say!
ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟの主人公にあるまじきこと
言ったよ この人｡
He doesn't have a shred of ambition!
向上心のかけらもないよ この人｡
Have you forgotten the three principles of JUMP?!
ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ三大原則を忘れたｱﾙか！
Friendship!
[Friendship]
友情 努力 勝利！
Effort!
[Effort]
[Victory]
Victory!
You can't have victory without effort!
努力なくして勝利はないね！
You can't defeat stronger rivals if you have no ambition!
向上心なくして強敵に
勝っていくことはできないｱﾙ！
No way...
ｲﾔだよ めんどくせえよ｡
Sounds like a pain.
Cause I mean, y'know...
だって お前さ あの…➡
It's a pain.
めんどくせえよ｡
Nothing's more painful than, y'know...
何が めんどくさいってさぁ➡
For example...
あのさぁ 例えばさ➡
Man, this is a pain.
うわっ めんどくせえよ！
もう例えるのも めんどくせえよ｡
Giving an example is a pain.
どんだけ めんどくせえんだよ！
How much pain are you in?!
Besides, did you plan out a basic outline for your training?
大体 お前ら
修行って具体的に➡
何やるかﾌﾟﾗﾝは決まってんの？
You're both saying that just 'cause everyone's doing it, right?
どうせ 周りのみんなが
やってるから➡
雰囲気で言ってるだけだろう
修行って言いたいだけだろう｡
You just wanted to talk about training.
修行さえやっときゃ ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟっぽく
なるとか 大間違いなんだよ｡
If you think that training will make this show more JUMP-like, you're wrong.
よそはよそ うちはうちだ｡
They're them. We're us.
If you want to train that badly, you can go live in some other anime.
そんなに修行やりたいんなら
他のｱﾆﾒんちの子になりな｡
おかあさん!?
ただの怠け者のくせに➡
Mom?!
You're saying things like a mom when you're just a lazy bum!
おかあさんみたいなこと
言ったよ！
Besides, the whole "Friendship, Effort, Victory" thing is so old-school.
そもそも 今どき
友情･努力･勝利なんて➡
流行んねんだよ！
何十年前に作ったｽﾛｰｶﾞﾝ➡
Stop clinging to a slogan from dozens of years ago.
引きずってるんだよ！
時代は流れてるんだよ!!
The world has moved on.
茨木は もう死んだんだよ！
Ibaragi is dead.
[Note: This is referring to Masahiko Ibaragi - Former editor-in-chief of Shonen JUMP]
He hasn't died yet!
死んでませんよ！ 『ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ･ｽｸｴｱ』の
編集長としてがんばってます!!
He's working hard as the editor-in-chief for JUMP SQ!
[Note: JUMP SQ is a Monthly JUMP magazine targeted for older teens and young adults.]
Besides, a training arc just consists of boring tasks.
だいたい
修行編なんて地味な作業➡
視聴者のｳｹがいいわけねえだろ！
That's not going to get you ratings.
And it's tiring for us, too.
こっちも しんどいだけだし｡
The ones that can get away with stuff like that,
ｱﾚができるのはな 必殺技とか
派手な演出ができたり➡
are shows with flashy special attacks and effects...
[Note: Example used here is from Dxxxxn Baxx's Kamehameha]
修行自体が斬新な
選ばれたﾔﾂらだけなんだよ｡
Or the training itself is innovative. It only works for a select few.
[Note: Example used here is from JxJx's Bxxxxxe Adventure Part 2 training.]
It's an area beyond our reach.
ｵﾚたちが手を出していい
領域じゃねえんだ！
最低だよ この人は…｡
This guy's despicable.
He's bringing up shady topics just because he doesn't want to train.
自分が
修行やりたくないばっかりに➡
とんでもない話 持ち出してるよ｡
それとも何？
Or what?
You two have an innovative, yet visually stunning training method in mind?
お前ら 斬新かつ
絵的に画面が持つ修行方法とか➡
考えてるの？
何も考えてねえだろ？
Of course you don't!
You just want to train, right?
どうぜ ﾌﾜｯと修行やりたいとか
言ってるだけだろ？
I do too!
考えてるもん！
私 ちゃんと考えてるｱﾙよ｡
I do have an actual plan!
何だよ じゃあ言ってみろよ｡
うん！
Oh? Then let me hear it.
とりあえずは あれｱﾙ…
山に こもるｱﾙ｡
First, we do that...
Camp out in the mountains.
ﾍﾞﾀだね で？
こもってどうするの？
Typical.
And? What do you do there?
That thing, uh...
(神楽)ｱﾚ… あの… く… ｸﾏに！
With bears.
Where you fight bears to hone your natural instincts?
戦いを挑んで野性の勘でも
身につけますか｡
That's old.
古り～んだよ！ そんなこともう
やり尽くされてんだよ｡
That idea's been done to death.
はぁ～！
Where it holds your feet as you do sit-ups.
(神楽)足 持ってもらって
腹筋とかするｱﾙ｡
Use the bear more effectively!
ｸﾏを有効に使え！
どんなｸﾏの使い方してんだ!!
How can you use a bear that way?!
ﾑﾀﾞ使いもいいところだろ！
ｸﾏを活かせよ!!
That's such a waste!
Let the bear do its thing!
(神楽)あぁ そっか｡
Oh, I see.
You call that doing its thing?!
どんな活かし方だ～！
Why is the bear training now?!
何で ｸﾏの修行になってるんだよ！
こんなん その辺のｽﾎﾟｰﾂｼﾞﾑでも➡
You could do kind this kind of stuff in a gym!
できるだろ！ ｲﾝｽﾄﾗｸﾀｰで十分だろ
もっと 違う…➡
A fitness instructor could handle that!
You need something different...
何でだ～！
Why?!
You're not even doing anything anymore!
これ もはや お前
何もしてねえだろ!!
And you're back from the mountains!
山から帰ってきてるし！
It's pretty innovative!
かなり斬新ｱﾙ…！
斬新すぎるだろ！
It's way too innovative!
修行してねえもん！
何も してねえもん!!
You're not even training!
Not doing anything!
(お妙)最近 どうも
様子がおかしいと思ったら➡
So that's why you've been behaving so oddly the past few days, Shin-chan.
そういうことだったのね
新ちゃん｡
やっぱり あなたも侍の子ね｡
You really are the son of a samurai.
S-Sis...
あっ 姉上｡
Why didn't you come to me sooner?
(お妙)そんなことなら
どうして もっと早く➡
私に相談してくれなかったの？
す すみません｡
I-I'm sorry.
I guess I was embarrassed or I wanted to keep it a secret...
照れくさかったっていうか
内緒にしたかったっていうか…｡
(お妙)あんなﾀﾞﾒな大人に任せたら
成長するどころか➡
If you rely on that failure of an adult, forget about improving. You'll only get worse.
劣化の一途をたどるばかりだわ｡
You say that when I'm sitting right here?
目の前で言うんだ それ｡
私に任せなさい｡
Leave it to me.
あなたたちを きっと
ﾜﾝﾗﾝｸ上の侍に導いてあげる｡
I promise I'll help you two become a top-notch samurai.
いい ２人ともよく聞いてね｡
Now listen carefully, you two.
The desire to become stronger and the desire to become more beautiful
強くなりたいとか
きれいになりたいとか➡
まったく違う物に見えて
実は みな同じなの｡
may appear different, but are actually the same.
つまり
自分を変えたいという欲求ね｡
In other words, you have a desire to change yourself...
ﾀﾞｲｴｯﾄをする際 食事制限より➡
Did you know that when you go on a diet,
there's something more important than limiting how much you eat?
もっと
大事なことがあるのを知ってる？
それは 痩せた自分の体を
思い描くこと｡
That would be to picture what you look like after you've lost weight.
理想像が目的地と言ってもいいわ｡
You could say that your goal is to reach that ideal.
People are unable to run down a path with no goal,
人はｺﾞｰﾙのない道のりを
走ることは できないけれど➡
but once they have a goal, they can continue to run any path no matter how long it is.
ｺﾞｰﾙがあれば どんな長い道のりも
走っていくことができるの｡
強くなるのも一緒｡
The same goes for becoming stronger.
自分が
どんなふうになりたいのか➡
Picture a basic image of how you want to become.
具体的に思い描く｡
If you have a goal in mind, you can work towards that goal little by little.
目的を設けることによって
ちょっとずつでも➡
[The Strongest]
そこへ向かって にじり寄って
行くことができるのよ｡
さぁ みんな
この紙に いったいどんなふうに➡
Okay, everyone.
Write down how you want to become stronger on this sheet of paper.
強くなりたいか描いて｡
This may seem like a roundabout way of doing this, but it's important.
遠回りに見えるけど
とても大切なことなのよ｡
Hmm... I see.
う～ん… なるほど
女性ならではの観点ですね｡
A perspective only a woman could have.
考えたこともないｱﾙ
結構 難しいｱﾙな｡
I've never thought of it that way.
This is pretty hard.
[I want my hair to become straight.]
Why are you the first one to finish writing?!
何で ｱﾝﾀが
いの一番に書いてんだよ！
And he doesn't look like he has any intention of becoming stronger!
しかも 強くなる気
まったくないよ この人！
I'm also done.
私も できたｱﾙ｡
[Fangs]
[Claws]
Can we move past that already?!
ｿｲﾂは もういいって
言ってんだろ！
何で さっきから自分そっちのけで
ｸﾏを育てることに➡
Why are you so focused on training a bear instead of yourself?!
夢中になってるの！
つうか その口の血 何？
And what's that blood around his mouth?!
Don't tell me it's that instructor?!
まさか ｲﾝｽﾄﾗｸﾀｰか！
さっきのｲﾝｽﾄﾗｸﾀｰか!?
Is it that fitness instructor?!
姉上も言ってやってくださいよ｡
You should say something, Sis.
う～ん みんな
いまいち踏み込みが足りないわね｡
You're still holding back.
You need to get over being shy.
照れが捨てきれてないわ｡
そういう問題なんですか!?
Is that the problem here?!
いくらｺﾞｰﾙを設けても
手が届かなきゃ➡
If you set a goal that isn't reachable,
you might as well not have a goal.
ｺﾞｰﾙがないのと一緒よ｡
ちゃんと
現実を見据えて➡
You need to keep your feet on the ground when you set your goal.
地に足のついた
目標を立てなきゃ｡
足がつくどころか
飛んでるんですけど!?
Not only are your feet off the ground, it's flying off into the air!!
何に なろうとしてるんですか
姉上!!
What are you trying to become, Sis?!
まったく別人 っていうか
別の生物じゃないですか!!
Isn't this a totally different person...
No... a totally different life form?!
つうか あの短時間で
どんだけ描き込んでんの！
And how did you draw this in such a short time?!
うますぎでしょ！ あれっ…｡
That's amazing!
Huh? Wait...
っていうか…｡ おい!!
Heyyyyy?!
なんで こんなところに
また ｲﾝｽﾄﾗｸﾀｰがいるんだよ!!
Why is that instructor here?!
ｸﾏに襲われているところを
見かけて 助けにきたのよ｡
It came to save him after seeing him attacked by the bear.
なんで さっきのやつから
話が繋がってんだよ！
Why are you picking up the story where the last picture left off?!
なんで
紙芝居になってんだよ!!
Why is this turning into a picture story?!
Hey, now.
(長谷川)おいおい｡
You'll never get stronger by taking drawing lessons.
(長谷川)お絵かき教室なんぞ
やってても➡
永遠に強くなんて
なりゃしねえぜ？
Hasegawa-san!
長谷川さん!?
[Everything turns to ashes.]
ｵﾚに任せな｡
ぱっつぁん じょうちゃん｡
Pattsan, little lady, leave it to me.
つうか この人 さり気なく
超怖い絵 描いてるんですけど！
And yeah, this guy drew a really scary picture!
何あれ!?
What the hell is that?!
A great player may not necessarily become a great coach.
(長谷川)名選手が名監督に
なるとは限らねえ｡
ｵﾚは 確かに非力だが➡
Though I may be powerless,
I can still offer shining guidance to a few lost lambs as your elder in life.
人生の先輩として
迷える子羊たちを➡
光に導くことはできる｡
No way!
ｲﾔなんですけど!!
光っていうか➡
What do you mean, shining?!
地獄の業火に
導こうとしてるんですけど!!
You're leading us into the fires of hell!
The whole story's drawn there!
絵がすべて
物語ってるんですけど!!
Just listen...
まぁ 聞いてくれ｡
As someone who's fallen from the very top to the very bottom, I can see things others can't.
てっぺんから どん底に落ちた
ｵﾚだからこそ➡
見えるものがある｡
Listen up.
(長谷川)いいか 世の中
でかいﾔﾏを 一発狙おうとか➡
In this world, people who live their lives
一発で 形勢を
逆転してやろうとか➡
by trying to climb a huge mountain in one go
そういう 雑な生き方を
しているﾔﾂは 必ず転ぶ｡
or trying to reverse a situation in one shot will definitely slip.
(歓声)
Sure, it might work once.
(長谷川)そりゃ １度くらい
うまくいことも あるかもしれん｡
だが そういうﾔﾂは
調子に乗って➡
But then they get cocky and throw big money after the same dark horse.
同じ大穴に
また大金を賭ける｡
幸運は 二度とは続かない｡
Luck doesn't strike twice.
気づいたときには ｽｶﾝﾋﾟﾝだ｡
Next thing you know, you're broke.
Wait, you only lost in a horse race.
いや… ｱﾝﾀ
競馬に負けただけじゃん｡
You're saying the whole world should burn in hell just from losing in a horse race?
競馬に 負けただけで
世界燃えろとか言ってんの!?
I'm saying that I can't beat people who work their way up little by little.
(長谷川)結局 堅実に地道に
ｺﾂｺﾂ努力してるﾔﾂには➡
敵わないって話だ｡
That's right.
(長谷川)そう たった１発で
強くなろうなんて➡
Those who want to instantly become strong
考えてる連中は 所詮➡
can never defeat those who have worked hard year after year.
何年も 何十年も日々
地味に 鍛錬を繰り返すﾔﾂらに➡
勝つことなんて
できやしねえんだ｡
生活と修行を
切り離して考えている時点で➡
When you consider training as separate from your daily lifestyle, you're already a drop-out.
お前らは問題外｡ いいか｡
Got it?
(長谷川)修行ってのは
今日 始めようとか➡
Training isn't something that you just start today or tomorrow.
明日から始めようとか
そういうものじゃねえんだ｡
You begin training the day you're born.
この世に 生まれ出でたときから
もう 始まってんだよ｡
要するにな 大上段に構えて
やるもんじゃねんだ 修行なんて｡
In other words, training isn't anything worth fussing about.
小さなことでもいい｡
Every little task you do can be considered training.
The point is to consistently perform these those tasks on a day-to-day basis.
いかに 日々の生活の中に
溶け込ませ➡
繰り返し ｺﾂｺﾂ
続けていくかが重要なんだ｡
こんな話を知っているか
お前たち｡
Have you heard this story before?
Once, there was a neat freak and a dirty slob.
[Dirty ]
[Clean]
(長谷川)あるところに
たいへん きれい好きな男と➡
不潔な男がいた｡
The man who was a neat freak would always sit down when taking a piss.
きれい好きな男は
小便をするとき➡
いつも 便座に座って
用を足した｡
So he wouldn't splatter any on the floor.
小便の飛沫が
床に飛ばないようにだ｡
一方 不潔な男は
そんなことを一切 気にしない｡
Meanwhile, the man who was a dirty slob paid no heed.
He always took care of his business standing, regardless of how much he got on the floor.
どれだけ 飛沫が飛ぼうと
立って用を足した｡
ごく些細な違いだ｡
A very slight difference.
誰も 気に留めないような｡
One that wouldn't attract anyone's attention.
But what do you think would happen if this continued for several decades?
だが この小さな違いが➡
何十年も
積み重なればどうなると思う？
(長谷川)きれい好きな男の厠は
相変わらず きれいだったが➡
The neat freak's toilet was always clean, but his legs became thinner as he aged.
その足は 老いていく度
細く痩せていった｡
逆に 不潔な男の足は➡
While the dirty slob's legs became thicker as he aged.
老いてもなお 太く
たくましかった｡
One did his business standing. One did his business sitting.
立って用を足す男
座って用を足す男｡
筋肉を使う者と
筋肉を使わない者｡
One who used his muscles. One who didn't use his muscles.
Who could predict that such a slight difference
誰が予想した？
たった それだけの違いが➡
would end up...
まさか 最終的に…｡
determining the victor in the Battle of Sekigahara.
[Note: The Battle of Sekigahara - The decisive battle that made way for the Tokugawa Shogunate.]
(長谷川)関が原の勝敗を
決めることになるなんて｡
Yes.
そう その男たちこそ➡
The two men were Ieyasu Tokugawa and Mitsunari Ishida!
徳川 家康と 石田 三成だ｡
ｳｿをつけ!!
なんでお前が➡
Stop lying!
How could you know how Ieyasu and Mitsunari took a piss?!
家康と三成の
小便のしかた 知ってんだよ!!
How could a kick determine victory in a battle?!
なんで 蹴りで
戦争の勝敗 決めてんだよ!!
The Battle of Sekigahara went into overtime
(長谷川)関が原って
延長戦にもつれこんで➡
最終的に ＰＫ戦に
なったらしいよ｡
and was decided by penalty kicks, I heard.
Why?!
なんでだ!! つうかＰＫでも
なんでもねえよ こんなの!!
And this has nothing to do with penalty kicks!
I'm just saying, Ieyasu pretended to be a dirty slob when in reality,
要するに 家康は
不潔のふりをして➡
実は 密かに
足を鍛えるために➡
he was standing as he pissed to build leg muscles.
立って 小便をしていたんだな｡
普通だろ!!
That's normal!
敵をあざむき
日々 ｺﾂｺﾂと➡
He trained little by little, day by day, while fooling the enemy.
地道に修行を
積み重ねていたんだよ｡
What a fearsome man, yeah?
恐るべき男だろ｡
修行でも何でもねえよ こんなの｡
That wouldn't be called training!
地味すぎるだろ!!
It's too normal!
The story continues...
(長谷川)余談だがね 家康に
この修行方法を進言したのは➡
[Note: Tenkai was a Buddhist monk who is said to have served Ieyasu.]
Ieyasu learned this secret form of training from a monk named Tenkai...
天海という僧と
言われているんだが｡
どんな進言してんだよ！
What the hell were those monks preaching?!
The true identity of Tenkai,
(長谷川)家康に寵愛され➡
known as the man who controlled the Edo Bakufu behind the scenes after earning Ieyasu's favor,
江戸幕府の影の支配者と呼ばれた
この天海の正体…➡
was rumored to be the man responsible for the Incident at Honno-ji and later killed by Hideyoshi...
[Note: Incident at Honno-ji is a historical event where Nobunaga Oda was assassinated by Mitsuhide Akechi at the Honno-ji temple.]
ｳﾜｻじゃ なんと
本能寺の変を起こし➡
秀吉に討ち取られた あの…➡
Mitsuhide Akechi's...
明智 光秀の…➡
fitness instructor.
[Note: There is a theory in Japanese history of Tenkai possibly being Mitsuhide Akechi.]
ｲﾝｽﾄﾗｸﾀｰだったらしい！
またお前かい～!!
You again?!
I've never heard a rumor like that!
聞いたことねえよ そんなｳﾜｻ！
And how long are you people going to drag on that instructor thing?!
つうか ｵﾒｴら
どんだけ ｲﾝｽﾄﾗｸﾀｰ引っ張れば➡
気が済むんだよ!!
呪いでもかけられてんのか！
Have you been cursed by that instructor or something?!
ｲﾝｽﾄﾗｸﾀｰに!!
(桂)まぁまぁ➡
Now, now.
そう 声を荒立てるな｡
There's no need for shouting.
(桂)しょせん ﾊﾟﾝﾋﾟｰの戯言だ｡
It's merely nonsense from a commoner.
侍の行く道は
侍にしか照らせん…｡
Only a samurai can guide you down the path of a samurai.
桂さん！ 街を➡
Katsura-san!
He's...!
ﾏﾀﾞｵが焼き尽くした街を
雨で浄化している！
He's using rain to cleanse the city DORK burned down!
(桂)ﾘｰﾀﾞｰ｡ 新八君｡
Leader.
Shinpachi-kun.
ｵﾚが ｷﾐたちに
侍のなんたるかを教えよう！
I shall teach you the knowhow of the samurai!
Hasegawa-san is correct.
確かに 長谷川さんの言うとおり➡
Training should be a part of your daily life.
修行とは
日常の一部であるべきだ｡
だが ｷﾐたちに問おう｡
However, I have a question.
ｷﾐらが求める強さとは➡
Is the strength you seek merely physical strength?
単純な 肉体的な強さなのか？
それが 修行の果てに
ｷﾐらが求めるものなのか？
Is that what you seek from training?
(桂)そうだろう｡
Right.
The true purpose of training
修行の真の目的とは
己を極限まで追い込み➡
is to push you to your limits
and discover your true self that remains hidden in ordinary times.
日常では 表に出てこぬ➡
潜在する真の己を
見つけることにある｡
(２人)真の己！
Your true self...
Exactly!
そうだ!! それを見つけたとき➡
Once you've found that, you will not merely attain simple physical strength...
ｷﾐたちは 短絡的 かつ
肉体的な強さなどではない！
Yes! You will attain true strength!
そう！ 真の強さを得るんだ!!
かつて 真の己を見つけた
こんな男がいた…｡
Once, there was a man who discovered his true self.
♪♪～
He was a white-collar worker.
(桂)男は ｻﾗﾘｰﾏﾝ｡
He always woke up at the same time, always got on the train at the same time,
いつも 同じ時間に起き
いつも 同じ時刻の電車に乗り➡
いつも 同じ会社に行き➡
always went to the same workplace, and always went home at the same time.
いつも 同じ時間に帰宅する…｡
無遅刻 無欠勤｡
Never late. Never absent.
An excellent job performance.
業績も優秀｡
He was the very picture of diligence,
絵に描いたような
ﾏｼﾞﾒな男であったが➡
ﾊﾀから見れば
つまらぬ男であった…｡
but anyone that looked would find him a dull person.
However, the man never felt bored.
しかし…
男はそれを 退屈とは思わない｡
In fact, he had no interest in living his life any other way.
むしろ 他の生き方に
興味すら覚えなかった…｡
(桂)それは 寒さ厳しい冬の朝｡
It was a bone-chilling winter morning...
The man attempted to get on the usual train at the usual station at the usual time.
男は いつもと同じ駅 同じ時刻➡
同じ電車の扉から
乗車しようとした｡
But the difference was the presence of an old man standing in front of him.
しかし いつもと違ったのは➡
そこに 老人が立っていたんだ｡
男は老人に遠慮して➡
Out of consideration for the old man, the man boarded through a different door.
いつもと違う 隣の扉から
乗車した…｡
次の駅に着くと➡
When he reached the next station, the seat in front of the man was open.
男の目の前の座席が空いた｡
This was rush hour.
ﾗｯｼｭ時間だ… ふだんならば
こんなことはありえない｡
Under normal circumstances that would be impossible.
Nobody around him moved towards the seat, so the man had no choice but to sit down.
周りは 誰も座ろうとしないので➡
男はしかたなく座った｡
そうこうしていると
男の降りる駅に着く｡
After some more traveling, the train reached the man's stop.
降りるには 席を立ち➡
To get off, he needed to leave his seat and make his way through the crowded train to the exit.
満員の車内を掻き分けて
出口に行かねばならない｡
That was when the man thought...
そこで男は思った｡
"I'd rather get off at the next station and turn back instead of bothering all these people."
｢人の迷惑になるくらいならば➡
隣の駅で降りて
折り返せばいい｣と…｡
それが もうひとつの駅…➡
And then it was the next station...
And the next...
さらに もうひとつ… と なり➡
By the end, he'd decided to ride until the last stop.
しまいには 終点まで
行ってみようという気になった｡
｢そうだ… 今日くらい
遅刻してもいいじゃないか…｣｡
"Yes... What's wrong with being late today?"
And he finally arrived
そして 着いた場所…➡
それは 海だった…｡
at the beach.
(桂)大海を前に 男は感じた｡
As the man stood in front of the ocean, he realized
いかに 己が小さき者であるか…｡
that he was such a tiny existence...
いかに 自分が
狭い世界に住んできたか…｡
That he'd been living in his own little world...
そして 男は会社を辞め
旅に出た…｡
And so the man quit his job and went on a journey.
Yes, that was when he finally realized his true self hidden within and attained true strength.
そう！ 彼はその時 ようやく➡
潜在していた 真の己に気づき➡
真の強さを 手に入れたんだ！
なんでだ～!!
Why?!
うぉ～っ!!
おい～!!
Wow!
No!
You're not supposed to be impressed by that!
そこ 感銘受けるところじゃ
ねえだろ～!!
And your flashbacks are always too long!
だいたい ｵﾒｴの回想は
いつも長すぎるんだよ!!
And why would his true self be a bear?!
つうか なんで
真の己の姿が ｸﾏなんだよっ!!
なんで さっきの
神楽ちゃんの絵から➡
Why are you making connections with Kagura-chan's picture?!
つながってんだよっ!!
いやぁ～ 昨日 ﾒｶﾞﾄﾞﾗｲﾌﾞで➡
Well, I was up all night yesterday playing Altered Beast on Mega Drive.
[Note: Mega Drive was called Sega Genesis in the United States.]
『獣王記』を徹夜でやってたから｡
理由になってねえんだよっ!!
That's not a reason!
(桂)いやぁ
でも 超 強そうじゃん ｸﾏ｡
But the bear's really strong.
短絡的すぎるだろ！ どう考えても
肉体的な強さだろ ｿﾚ！
That's simplifying things too much!
That only covers physical strength, no matter how you look at it!
ｳﾑ… では さっそく
本題へ移ろう｡
Then I'll get to the subject at hand.
What training is required to become a true samurai.
[Samurai]
(桂)真の 侍になるための修行とは
何かという話に｡
かつて ｵﾚと銀時は
同じ学び舎で文武を修めた｡
Long ago, Gintoki and I trained in both the pen and the sword at the same school.
そう そのときの
我らの恩師の教え➡
Yes, if I directly pass on the instruction received from our honorable teacher,
そのまま ｷﾐらに伝授すれば…➡
必ずや 我らのような
真の侍になれるはず｡
you should be able to become a true samurai like us.
銀さんたちが
かつてやった修行を ﾎﾞｸらが…｡
We'll go through your former training...?
うむ｡
おい ﾂﾞﾗ よせ！
Hey, cut it out, Zura.
あの修行は 危険すぎる｡
ｺｲﾂらには まだ…｡
That training's too dangerous.
It's still too early for them...
やれるさ… 彼らなら｡
They can handle it.
彼らは ただ
強くなりたいのとはわけが違う｡
They do not merely seek strength.
銀時… お前の隣で戦いたいのさ｡
Gintoki.
They want to fight by your side.
それが ちょとやそっとの苦行で
負けると思うか？
Do you think a little hardship will be enough to beat them down?
そんなこと
お前が いちばんわかっておろう｡
You should know the answer very well.
The training will be harsh, but I'm sure you can endure it.
厳しい修行になるが
耐えられるな？
♪♪～
うむ… いい目だ｡
I like the look in your eyes.
はい じゃあ まず
このｶﾒの甲羅を背負ってください｡
Okay, then start by putting these turtle shells on your back.
重いだろうが 外してはいかんぞ｡
They're heavy, but you're not allowed to remove them.
Okay, now you have to go search for a certain item while wearing those weights.
よし！ じゃあ ｷﾐたちには
その ｵﾓﾘを背負ったまま➡
あるものを探してもらう｡
I'm going to throw this rock that has "Katsura" written on it outside.
この ｢桂｣と書いた石ころ｡
これを 今から外に投げる｡
[Katsura]
｢桂｣と書いてある以外は
何の変哲もない この石ころを➡
You must discern this perfectly ordinary stone, besides for the "Katsura" written on it,
他の石と見分けて拾ってくるんだ｡
from the other stones, and bring it back here.
There's only one stone.
石は１つしかない｡
拾ってこれなかったほうは➡
Whoever doesn't bring it back doesn't get dinner tonight.
今日の晩飯は 抜きだ｡
ちなみに➡
And just so you know, you won't be able to pick up a random stone and write "Katsura" on it.
そのへんの石ころを拾って
｢桂｣と書いて持ってきてもﾑﾀﾞだぞ｡
字を見れば わかるからな！
I can tell from the handwriting.
ｱｯﾊｯﾊｯﾊ！
よし じゃあいくぞ…｡
Okay, then go!
(２人)ｵﾗ～ｯ!!
なんだよ これ！
なんなんだよ この修行！
What is this?!
What is this training?!
完全に
どっかで見たことあるぞ ｵｲ!!
We've definitely seen this before!
[Note: Again, a training done in Dxxxxn Baxx. Manga Vol. 3 to be specific.]
What?
なに？ どこかでﾊﾟｸられていたか｡
Has someone ripped me off?
ｵﾒｴが ﾊﾟｸったんだろうが!!
You're the one who ripped it off!
おかしいな？
確かに 師匠がこうして…｡
That's odd.
I remember our teacher doing the same...
何だ？ ｵﾒｴ… ｵﾒｴみてえのが
武天老子の弟子だとでも➡
What?
Are you trying to say that you're a student of Master Roshi?!
[Note: Master Roshi. Character from Dxxxxn Baxx.]
言い張るつもりか!!
おい ﾂﾞﾗ！
Hey, Zura.
ぜんぜん違う！ ﾊﾞｶなのお前｡
That's totally wrong.
You're the fool.
あれ？
こんなんじゃなかったっけ？
Huh?
This wasn't how it went?
違えよ ｵﾒｴ！
お前みたいなﾊﾞｶに➡
It wasn't.
It was a mistake to lend the entire Dragon Boozu series to an idiot like you.
[Note: Dragon Boozu is a Gin Tama parody of Dxxxxn Baxx.]
『ﾄﾞﾗｺﾞﾝﾎﾞｰｽﾞ』 全巻貸したのが
間違いだった｡
そうでしょう？
びっくりさせないでくださいよ｡
Right?
Don't surprise me, Gin-san.
銀さん｡
こんなﾊﾟﾁもんの修行で➡
I almost thought you became strong through this copycat training.
強くなったのかと思いましたよ｡
おいおい 勘弁してくれよ｡
Hey, give me a break.
It was totally different.
ぜんぜん違うよ
こんなんじゃねえっつうの｡
Nothing like this.
まず 甲羅じゃなくて
このｲﾝｽﾄﾗｸﾀｰを➡
First of all, we were carrying fitness instructors, not turtle shells.
１人ずつ背負ってだな｡
おい～！
Heeyyy!
いいかげんにしろよ ﾃﾒｴら!!
Cut it out, you freaks!
I told you to drop it already!
もう それはいいって
言ってんだろうが!!
つうか どっから出てきたんだよ
ｺｲﾂら!!
And where did these people come from?!
[Gin]
今から この ｢銀｣と書いた
ｲﾝｽﾄﾗｸﾀｰを外に投げる｡
I'm going to throw this instructor that has "Gin" written on it outside.
なんで投げるのも
ｲﾝｽﾄﾗｸﾀｰなんだよ!!
Why are the instructors the ones being thrown?!
拾ってこれなかったほうの
背中のｲﾝｽﾄﾗｸﾀｰは 晩飯抜きだ｡
The instructor on the back of the person who doesn't return them doesn't get dinner.
なんでだ!? ｲﾝｽﾄﾗｸﾀｰ
何も悪いことしてないだろ!!
Why?!
The instructor didn't do anything wrong!
ちなみに そのへんのｲﾝｽﾄﾗｸﾀｰを
拾ってきて➡
And you won't be able to pick up a random instructor and write "Gin" on it.
｢銀｣と書いて持ってきても
ﾑﾀﾞだからな｡
そのへんに
ｲﾝｽﾄﾗｸﾀｰ 落ちてねえよ!!
There aren't random instructors standing around!
I can tell from the handwriting.
字を見れば わかる｡
ｲﾝｽﾄﾗｸﾀｰの顔でわかれ!!
You can tell from the instructors' faces!
もうやってらんねえ！
I can't take this anymore!
We were fools for asking you people!
お前らに頼んだ
私たちが ﾊﾞｶだったね!!
もう 誰も頼りません！
We won't depend on anyone else!
強くなる方法は
自分たちで見つけます！
We'll find our own method of becoming stronger!
ありがとうございました!!
Thank you very much!
Just wait and see!
見とけよ！ ﾋﾞｯｸﾘするくらい
強くなってやるからな！
We'll become so strong you'll be shocked!
《それで… いいんだ》
That's how it should be.
己の道は 誰にも頼らず
己で決める｡
You must choose your own path by yourself.
修行第一関門 突破だな｡
They've cleared the first stage of training.
弱音なんか吐いたら
承知しないんだから｡
I won't go easy on them if they whine.
ｵﾚたちは
いつでも見守っているぞ｡
We're always watching over them.
そう ﾜﾀｼたちは…｡
Yes, because we are...
(銀時たち)あなたたちの
人生のｲﾝｽﾄﾗｸﾀｰなのだから｡
your instructors in life.
[Preview]
Hijikata-san.
I think we screwed up.
Looks like we've been captured.
Yes. And after getting the spotlight for the first time in 19 episodes.
The next episode:
"Zip Up Your Fly Nice and slowly." Women wouldn't understand.
[Hijikata and Okita are locked in a room by the mysterious villain Jigsaw.]
[Fear and paranoia abound... Forced to make a choice... The game for these two men's lives begins.]
[See you next time.]